# Himanshu Uppal (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Web Development, Project Management, Client Management, Database Development, Requirement Gathering, Entity framework, MySQL, AWS, GIT, Javascript



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months Current Company: Nagarro

Current Location: Gurgaon Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Web Development, Project Management, Client Management, Database Development, Requirement Gathering, Entity

framework, MySQL, AWS, GIT, Javascript

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 18-Jan-21 Last Active: 18-Jan-21

# **Summary**

Himanshu Uppal has 2.5 years of experience in the software industry. He has experience in Full Stack development using technologies such as React JS, .Net Core, Node JS, AWS, MySQL. He has worked on Node JS and .NET Core Framework projects using Web API.

# Work Experience

Nagarro as Software Engineer Aug 2018 to Till Date

Nagarro as Software Engineer Aug 2018 to Aug 2018

Organization Nagarro

Client Client is one of the famous chains of over 265 franchised fitness clubs located in the United States, Canada and most recently Australia.

Project overview Project involved the development for the process of managing members of

the clubs, managing orders of the health clubs, cancellation of the

Agreements signed by the members, credits posting on the account of

members for any unpaid payments, invoice creation for any item purchased

from the fitness club.

Technologies React JS, Node JS, AWS, MySQL, .Net Core

Responsibilities \* Involved in analysis of required functionality, task estimation

\* Designed application database

\* Worked on implementation of key modules and UI creation

Aricent (now Altran) as Software Developer Jan 2018 to Jun 2018

## **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Bhaskaracharya College of Applied Sciences in 2015

PG: MCA (Computers) from Bharati Vidhyapeeth Institute of Computer Applications and Management in 2018

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Use	d Experience
React JS, Node JS, C#		
.Net Core, JavaScript		
AWS, git		
MySQL, sql server		
sequelize (Node js), Entity framework		
OOP/D, Microservices Architecture		
REST APIs, Database Modelling		

### **Affirmative Action**

**Work Authorization** 

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time